## MUHAMMAD ZIAD ABUSAA

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

+10 years experience of software development and +5 years of experience in cloud technologies . Well-versed in technology to create systems that are reliable and user-friendly. Skilled leader who has the proven ability to motivate, educate, and manage a team of professionals to build applications and effectively track changes.

#### **WORK HISTORY**

# TECH TEAM LEAD (CLOUD NATIVE APPLICATIONS), THIQAH BUSINESS SERVICES



1/9/2019 - Present

## PRODUCT MANAGER / TEAM LEAD, NETWAYS, RIYADH



1/1/2018 - 1/8/2019

### TECHNICAL TEAM LEADER, NETWAYS, RIYADH



1/1/2017 - 30/12/2017

## SENIOR SOLUTION DESIGNER, NETWAYS, RIYADH



1/12/2012 - 1/1/2017

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER, OGER SYSTEMS, RIYADH

GGER SYSTEMS

1/1/2010 – 30/11/2012

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

CKA: Certified Kubernetes

Administrator

Certification Number: LF-kg8hjq9m42

Microsoft Certified: DevOps Engineer

Expert

Certification Number: H584-3759

Microsoft Certified: Azure Developer

Associate

Certification Number: H584-3619

Microsoft® Certified Solutions Expert:

Productivity

Certification Number: G421-5726



Microsoft® Certified Solutions

Associate: Office 365

Certification Number: G421-5525

Microsoft Certified Professional Certification Number: E933-3478



#### SKILLS

- Containers orchestration / Kubernetes. "Certified"
- Azure DevOps. "Certified"
- Containerization and Docker.
- Kubernetes management and monitoring: Rancher / Prometheus / Grafana.
- Team management / leadership
- .NET Core / Framework.
- Client Side Development
- SharePoint "Certified"
- Office 365 Understanding
- CRM Understanding
- BizTalk Understanding
- K2 Understanding
- Angular
- Project Scoping
- Application design
- Preparing demos and related presentation
- Product owner / scrum master / solution management
- System / Business analysis

## PROFESSIONAL ACHIEVEMENTS

#### PLATFORM AND TRANSFORMATION

- Leading organization transformation using Docker and Kubernetes.
- Built multiple k8s clusters "self hosted" for multi environments including production environment.
- Used k8s managed service by cloud providers.

- Used management tools for k8s such as rancher.
- Used monitoring tools for k8s Prometheus / Grafana

#### **INTERNET AND ESERVICES PROJECTS**

- Amaaly: .NET Core / Docker / Kubernetes.
- Ministry of commerce / Franchise : .NET Core / Angular
- Ministry of commerce / Maroof : .NET Core / Docker and Kubernetes .
- SFDA eservices project : .Net Core , Kubernetes , React
- Ministry of interior Mifon Project : Angular JS , Web Api , SharePoint , CRM
- GMCO internet website : SharePoint 2013 , Word Automation
- The centennial fund eServices website (eServices using .Net)
- Alrajhi Takaful Internet website (eServices using .Net)
- Council of Saudi Chambers Internet website: SharePoint 2010
- High Commission for the Development of Arrivadh website: SharePoint 2010

#### **ERP**

• RDCCI ERP web application (using asp.net web forms)

#### **INTRANET PROJECTS**

- Sanabil Intranet: SharePoint 2016 / CMS
- SASO Intranet: SharePoint 2010 / .Net / AngularJs / K2
- Ecra intranet: SharePoint 2013 / Word Automation
- GMCO intranet : SharePoint 2013 / CMS
- COE enterprise content management system : SharePoint
- AlSubaie intranet : SharePoint 2010
- Rivadh Chamber of Commerce Intranet: SharePoint 2010

#### **EDUCATION**

#### BACHELOR IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, UNIVERSITY OF JORDAN, AMMAN

2005-2009